# **Jerry Gretzinger**

19 Parkside Trail, Ballston Lake, NY 12019 518-368-1922

jgretz672@gmail.com

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Communications executive with over 20 years of experience in public relations, marketing, corporate communications and broadcast journalism. Expertise leading a communications team supporting higher education; high tech research, development and deployment programs for both public and private sectors; green and renewable energy programs; economic development initiatives and nonprofit healthcare organizations. A respected, skilled and creative communicator, writer and public speaker with a commitment to excellence.

#### **EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE**

# **SUNY Research Foundation / SUNY Polytechnic Institute**

Vice President, Strategic Communications and Public Relations

2014 - 2016

- Coordinate all internal and external marketing and communications efforts
- Lead a communications team with offices and staff in Albany, Utica and Rochester and maintain successful operational protocols
- Serve as the primary media interface and spokesperson and deliver key messages
- Identify compelling stories about the institution for local, national and international media to help drive positive public perception
- Create effective and accessible press releases and messaging from sometimes complex subjects for distribution to a wide variety of audiences
- Collaborate with representatives from Federal and State government offices and agencies, private companies, non-profit organizations and other academic institutions on joint announcements and events
- Establish communications and marketing plans for merger of two separate and unique higher education institutions and create a new unified branding identity
- Prepare and review speeches, letters to the editor, presentations and other materials intended for public use
- Coordinate interviews between journalists and appropriate faculty, staff, students and partners and prepare appropriate internal messaging and talking points
- Work with deans, faculty and department leaders to create marketing and communications materials to further awareness of the institution
- Serve as a representative in a variety of venues including business, technology, academic and community organizations and entities
- Oversee, foster and strengthen public relations in support of policy development
- Advise administration, faculty and staff on all matters pertaining to media, branding and public perception
- Lead social media initiatives ensuring consistent messaging and branding
- Oversee creation of internal monthly online newsletter
- Serve as project lead for development of new website
- Coordinate planning of major events and community outreach initiatives
- Serve on crisis management team

## **Independent Public Relations Consultant**

2006 - Present

- Construct marketing and public relations plans and prepare press releases and media advisories for small businesses and nonprofit healthcare organizations
- Focus heavily on engaging target audiences through social media

# WRGB-CBS 6 NEWS, Schenectady, NY

News Anchor/Reporter

2002 - 2014

- Anchor weekday newscasts
- Research, write and report daily news assignments
- · Maintain regular contact with sources in government, business, education and law enforcement
- Interview elected officials, business leaders and community members
- Write and produce creative human interest segments
- Prepare and post content on station website and social media sites
- · Report breaking news live from the field
- Host/MC community events as station representative and make public appearances

# WGGB-NEWS40, Springfield, MA

Reporter/Anchor

1999 - 2002

- Write, report daily news assignments
- Write, produce "On Your Side" investigative franchise reports
- · Report breaking news live from the field
- · Maintain regular contact with sources in government, business, education and law enforcement
- Fill-in anchor for all newscasts when necessary
- Write copy for newscasts
- Make public appearances

# Six Flags New England, Agawam, MA

**Public Relations Manager** 

1998-2000

- Serve as a public relations manager for the international theme park chain
- Assist with rebranding of new property and major attractions
- Lead the crisis management team
- Prepare media advisories, press releases and coordinate marketing events
- Serve as company spokesperson, write both internal and external newsletters as well as copy for use on company websites and brochures
- Prepare talking points for higher level management when addressing the press
- Serve as liaison with local and state government officials

## WWLP-TV22, Springfield, MA

Morning Anchor/Reporter/Weathercaster

1995 - 1998

- Anchor weekday morning and noon newscasts
- Supervise producer and approve all scripts
- Write, report daily news assignments
- · Maintain regular contact with sources in government, business, education and law enforcement
- Make public appearances
- Produce and deliver daily weather forecasts

## **NEWSCENTER 6, Wappingers Falls, NY**

Anchor/Reporter/Producer

1995

- Anchor and produce evening newscasts
- Report feature and general assignment stories
- Maintain regular contact with sources in government, business, education and law enforcement
- Host and produce community events program and talk show
- Shoot and edit videotape

# WTZA-TV 62, Kingston, NY

Reporter, Video Journalist

- Write, report daily news assignments
- · Shoot and edit video

## STAGE PRODUCTION EXPERIENCE

Has appeared in more than 150 productions, from New York City to New England. Notable roles include Sky Masterson in *Guys and Dolls*, Leo Bloom in *The Producers* and Billy Flynn in *Chicago*. Has performed around the Capital Region in musical revues at venues including Mac-Haydn Theatre, Proctors Theatre, Saratoga First Night, Saratoga Casino and Raceway and the Fort Salem Theater. Featured guest vocalist with Albany's Swing Docs big band and a member of the Singing Anchors, with newscasters Benita Zahn and Jessica Layton.

## **VOLUNTEER WORK**

- Equinox Thanksgiving Day Community Dinner, 2015 2016
- Albany Police Athletic League, 2009 2014
- Bus Stop Club, 2010 2014
- Muscular Dystrophy Association, 2009 2013
- Clifton Park Rec Youth Basketball Coach, 2011 2012
- St. Jude's Hospital, 2008 2009
- Make-a-Wish Foundation of Northeast New York, 2004 2006

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Arts, Communications, 1994 Marist College, Poughkeepsie, NY

## **AWARDS**

1999 Winner2002 Winner2003 NomineeAssociated PressAssociated PressAssociated PressFeature ReportFeature VideographyNews Series

2009 Nominee 2009 Winner 2009 Winner

NY EMMY Awards NY EMMY Awards New York State Broadcaster Association

Feature Report Children's Programming Feature Report

1993 - 1995